mercolahealthyskin.com 2019-03-30

# Mercola Policy on Security, Privacy and Website Terms of Use

## Effective Date: 03/07/2017

## Last Updated Date: 03/26/2019

This policy sets forth the type of information [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) collects from you via this website: [www.mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) (the "Website"), the way we use such information, and the procedures we use to keep such information confidential. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information.

[Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) takes every reasonable precaution to protect our users' personal information. When users submit sensitive information via the [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) website, their information is protected both online and off-line.

### Your Consent

By using the Website, you consent to the collection and use of certain information in the manner we describe and agree to be bound by the terms of use as set forth herein. By logging into your cart, you consent to periodic email notifications regarding the status of your check-out process. You may opt out of these any time after your initial notice.

^ Back to Top

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our policies, we will post those changes on this Website. Information collected before changes are made will be secured according to the Policy in place at the time such information is collected notwithstanding future changes to this Policy. The practices and policies in this Policy replace all previous notices or statements with respect to the same subject matter. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

^ Back to Top

### Opt-out or Termination of User Accounts

If users have opted out of all communication with the Website, or deleted/deactivated their account, [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) will not contact such users again nor will their personal information ever be used by us in any manner.

^ Back to Top

### Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please [contact us](https://shop.mercola.com/pages/ContactUs.aspx).

You may also contact us at:

**Mercola.com**  
125 SW 3rd Place Suite 205  
Cape Coral, FL 33991

**Mercola.com Health Resources, LLC**  
125 SW 3rd Place Suite 205  
Cape Coral, FL 33991

^ Back to Top

### Security

We are committed to preventing others from unauthorized access to the personal information you provide to us, and we maintain commercially reasonable procedures and technology designed for this purpose. The Website has reasonable technical and organizational security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under our control. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those security measures or use your personal information for improper purposes.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information, such as credit card number, that information is encrypted and is protected with the industry standard software, 256-bit SSL . While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just "surfing."

While we use 256-bit SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment.

^ Back to Top

### The Information We Collect

We request information from the user on our secure order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. We may store this information securely on our server. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user. This information is only shared with other companies who work on behalf of [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) to provide a product or service to you. Unless we tell you differently, these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us. We may also use this information to inform you of additional goods and services about which you might be interested or to customize your experience and use of the Website.

We may ask you for personally-identifying information in connection with a promotion or survey. Any email you receive from us, or third parties authorized by you to send email, will contain additional opt-out or unsubscribe options in the email with instructions on how to unsubscribe from receiving future emails.

If you want to send an item to your friend, like a gift card, we will ask for your friend's first name, last name, and email address. We will only use this information to complete your order and send the item to your friend. [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) stores this information for the sole purpose of processing this order and tracking the success of your order. Your friend may contact us at <https://shop.mercola.com/pages/ContactUs.aspx> to request that we remove this information from our database.

We may automatically gather general statistical information about our website and visitors, such as IP addresses, browsers, pages viewed, number of visitors, goods and services purchased, transactions completed, etc. To do this, we use action tags and cookies provided by our site analytics and marketing partners. Although these partners log the information coming from our site on our behalf, we authorize how that data may and may not be used.

^ Back to Top

### Children Under 13

We do not knowingly collect or use personal information from children under 13. We have no way of distinguishing the age of individuals who address our website, and so we carry out the same Privacy Policy for individuals of all ages. If a child has provided us with personal information, the parent or guardian should contact us to remove the information and opt out of promotional opportunities. If we learn that we have received personal information from an individual under the age of 13, we will delete the information.

^ Back to Top

### Log Files

Like most standard website servers, we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to other personally identifiable information.

^ Back to Top

### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies or similar technologies are used by [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) and our partners [e.g. lifestyle-publishing websites, etc.], affiliates, or analytics or service providers [e.g. online customer support provider, etc.]. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

**Why do we use these technologies?**

MANDATORY COOKIES

Minimum required for the site to function correctly and securely.

This website will:

  * Remember page to page information essential for completing forms
  * Remember cookie settings
  * Protect your personal information

PREFERENCE AND ANALYTICS

Used to improve your browsing experience.

This website will:

  * Retain preference settings and geographic information
  * Make sure the website looks consistent
  * Capture website usage to further improve experience

SOCIAL MEDIA AND ADVERTISING

Enables selected advertising relevant to you.

This website will:

  * Allow you to share pages with social networks like Facebook, Pinterest, and Twitter, etc.

The use of tracking technologies by our third party [partners, affiliates, service providers] is not covered by our privacy policy. Technology limitations do not enable us direct access or control over such technologies.

^ Back to Top

### The Way We Use Information

Our goal is to provide products that best meet your needs, therefore we evaluate your personal interactions with us in an effort to bring you the products which best suit your tastes. In addition, we use your information to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze site usage, to improve our content and product offerings, and to customize our site's content, layout, and services.

We may use your information to deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests, such as targeted banners, new products, services, and promotions. At times, we may ask you to provide us voluntarily with additional information regarding your personal or business interests, experience, or requests, which we may use to customize our products and services for you.

If you place a request for products or services, we use your personal information to ship your order; if the products or services are from a retail partner, we may provide your relevant information to that retailer for purposes of the transaction. If you establish a credit account with us or our providers, we collect additional information, including billing information, credit card number, and expiration date, and tracking information from checks or money orders.

If [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

In certain situations, Mercola.com may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also use or disclose information to resolve disputes or investigate problems. We may disclose or access information whenever we believe in good faith that the law so requires, such as to comply with a litigation, or that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or if we otherwise consider it necessary to do so to maintain service and improve our products and services.

We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers, to manage our website and to enhance our site based on the usage pattern data we receive. 

Category of Use | Example  
---|---  
Mandatory | 

We use security cookies to authenticate users, prevent fraudulent use of login credentials, and protect user data from unauthorized parties.

For example, they help protect your account from being accessed by anyone other than you to keep your information safe and secure.   
  
Preference and Analytics | 

We use analytic cookies to understand, improve, and research products you are interested in when accessing our websites from a computer or mobile device.

For example, we allow our websites to remember information that changes the way the site behaves or looks, such as your preferred language or the region you are in.

Loss of the information stored in a preference cookie may make the website experience less functional but should not prevent it from working.   
  
Social Media and Advertising | 

We use cookies and similar technologies to understand and deliver ads that are more relevant to you.

For example, some common applications of cookies are to select advertising based on what’s relevant to a user; to improve reporting on campaign performance; and to avoid showing ads the user has already seen. 

Additionally, we may use cookies to understand and improve how you are using social plugins to interact with our website and products. We may share information about this analysis with our partners.  
  
The content may not be available for use outside of the United States. Mercola.com makes no representation that any content is appropriate or available for use outside the United States, its territories, possessions and protectorates. If you choose to access the Site from other locations, you do so on your own initiative and at your own risk. You are responsible for complying with local laws, if and to the extent local laws are applicable. You specifically agree to comply with all applicable laws concerning the transmission of technical data exported from the United States or the country you reside in.

^ Back to Top

### Sharing with Service Providers

We may share your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. These services may include payment processing, fulfilling orders and delivering packages. 

^ Back to Top

### User Access and Choice

Upon request Mercola.com will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by making the change on your member information page, or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within a reasonable timeframe.

MAIL

**Mercola.com**  
125 SW 3rd Place Suite 205  
Cape Coral, FL 33991 

**Mercola.com Health Resources, LLC**  
125 SW 3rd Place Suite 205  
Cape Coral, FL 33991 

PHONE

**US Toll-Free:** 877-985-2695  
**Int'l Customers:** 239-599-9500

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

^ Back to Top

### Newsletter

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the instructions on our unsubscribe page.

^ Back to Top

### AP Writing Style

Mercola.com follows journalistic industry standards by using the Associated Press (AP) writing style. For consistency's sake, we sometimes change quoted text from other printed sources to reflect AP style, or to indicate that the usage is the exact language of the quoted text. Those changes and indications will appear in brackets within the text.

^ Back to Top

### Email-A-Friend

If a user elects to use our Email-A-Friend service for informing a friend about an article, we will ask for your friend's name and email address. Mercola.com will only use this information send the article to your friend, and does not retain the information once the request has been completed.

^ Back to Top

### Links

The Web site contains links to other sites. [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. By including links to other websites, we neither endorse such sites nor guarantee that the information they contain is accurate. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site to read the privacy statements of every linked website as the privacy policies of each may differ from ours. This privacy statement applies solely to the [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) website.

^ Back to Top

### Social Media Widgets

Our Site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

^ Back to Top

### Public Profiles

The profile you create on the site will be publicly accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of your profile through your account portal.

^ Back to Top

### Third Party Advertising

We do not accept any paid advertisements on [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/). Mercola.com also does not host or receive funding from the display of commercial content. Any services or products recommended and/or offered in the newsletter or elsewhere on [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) have gone through extensive review before such recommendations, and based on that review were recommended and/or offered.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/). Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) users based on their visit to [Mercola.com](https://www.mercola.com/) and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](https://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of advertising messages. You will continue to receive generic ads.

We also use Google AdSense to publish ads on this site. When you view or click on an ad, a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on this and other Web sites. You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google's Advertising and Privacy page: <https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

^ Back to Top

### Unsolicited Ideas

We welcome feedback, questions, and comments about our products, services, and this Website. As a general policy, we do not accept unsolicited ideas for products or services through this Website. All communications and other materials (including, without limitation, unsolicited ideas, photographs, drawings, suggestions, or materials) you send to this Website by e-mail or otherwise are and shall remain the sole and exclusive property of Mercola.com and may be used by us for any purpose whatsoever, commercial or otherwise, without compensation to you.

^ Back to Top

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

^ Back to Top
